Guide to the Mary McCarthy Papers, circa 1915-2013 (bulk 1960-1989)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I: WRITINGS
  - Published Books
    - The Company She Keeps (1942)
      - Setting copy: Chapter 3. The Man in the Brooks Brothers Shirt (Folder 3.4)
      - Setting copy: Chapter 4. The Genial Host (Folder 3.5)
      - Setting copy: Chapter 5. Portrait of the Intellectual as a Yale Man, p. 111-189 (Folders 3.6 - 3.8)
      - Setting copy: Chapter 5. Portrait of the Intellectual as a Yale Man, p. 1-79 (Folders 3.9 - 3.10)
      - Setting copy: Chapter 6. Ghostly Father, I Confess, p. 1-37 (Folder 3.11)
      - Setting copy: Chapter 6. Ghostly Father, I Confess, p. 190-234 (Folders 3.12 - 3.13)
      - Publisher's correspondence, 1938-1943 (Folders 4.1 - 4.5)
      - Jacket dummy (Folder 4.6)
      - Letter to Cushing Strout regarding the character "Jim,", 27 July 1984 (Folder 394.5)
      - Reader mail, 1941-1959, undated (Folders 4.7 - 4.8)
      - Reviews, 1942-1957 (Folder 4.9)
      - Reviews (Folder 307.7)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 300.4)
      - Reviews of Italian edition (Gli Uomini della Sua Vita ), 1982 (Folder 4.10)
    - The Oasis (1949)
      - Letter from R. L. Simon of Simon and Schuster, and biographical notes, 17 Feb 1942 (Folder 5.1)
      - Original typescript, p. 1-96 (Folders 5.1 - 5.5)
      - Early variants (Folder 5.6)
      - Revised typescript, p. 1-101 (Folders 5.7 - 5.10)
      - Reader mail (Folder 5.11)
      - Reviews, 1949, 1988 (Folder 5.12)
      - Reviews, 1949-1950, undated (Folders 307.8 - 307.10)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.3)
      - Copy of Horizon with letter from Reuel Wilson to Bowden Broadwater, 1949, 1990 (Folder 5.13)
    - Cast A Cold Eye (1950)
      - Typescript variants: "The Weeds" (Folder 6.1)
      - Typescript draft: "The Cicerone," p. 18-28 (possibly original version); and typescript variants (Folder 6.2)
      - Typescript draft: "The Cicerone," p. 1-30 ("earlyish version") (Folder 6.3)
      - Typescript draft: "The Friend of the Family," p. 1-39 (Folder 6.4)
      - Manuscript draft: "The Old Men" (Folder 6.5)
      - Typescript draft: "The Old Men," p. 1-15; "earlier version," p. 2-14 (Folder 6.6)
      - Manuscript variant: "C.Y.E." (Folder 6.7)
      - Typescript variants: "C.Y.E." (Folders 6.8 - 6.9)
      - Editorial reader's notes on "Yonder Peasant,", 1948 (Folder 6.10)
      - French translation of "The Old Men," Adam, Oct 1966 (Folder 6.11)
      - American reviews, 1950 (Folder 6.12)
      - English reviews, 1952 (Folder 6.13)
    - The Groves of Academe (1952)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter 1, version A (Folder 7.1)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter 3, version A (Folder 7.2)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter 3, version 2 (Folder 7.3)
      - Typescript draft: Chapters 8-11, early version (Folders 7.4 - 7.7)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter 1 (Folder 7.8)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter 3 (Folder 7.9)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter 6 (Folder 7.10)
      - Discarded material (Folders 7.11 - 7.13)
      - Setting copy, chapters. 2-13 (Folders 8.1 - 8.12)
      - Manuscript: lecture on The Groves of Academe, University of Missouri, 1952 (Folder 8.13)
      - unidentified typescript (Folder 302.4)
      - Reader mail (Folder 8.14)
      - Reviews, 1950-1953, undated (Folders 8.15 - 8.17)
      - Reviews (Folder 307.11)
    - A Charmed Life (1955)
      - Typescript: Notes (Folder 9.1)
      - Typescript: "Further notes ... " (Folder 9.2)
      - Typescript for agent, Brandt and Brandt (Folder f.9.3)
      - Typescript: Chapters 6-8 variants (Folders 9.4 - 9.6)
      - Typescript: Chapters 11-13 variants (Folders 9.7 - 9.9)
      - Setting copy: Chapters 1-3, p. 1-68 (Folders 9.10 - 9.12)
      - Setting copy: Chapters 4-13, p. 69-242 (Folders 10.1 - 10.10)
      - Book Jackets (Folder 316.2)
      - American reviews, 1955-1956, 1959, undated (Folders 10.11 - 10.14)
      - English reviews (Folder 10.15)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 300.3)
    - Sights and Spectacles (1956)
      - Setting copy: A Prince of Shreds and Patches, 1956 (Folder 11.1)
      - English reviews (Folder 11.2)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.6)
    - Venice Observed (1956)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.6)
    - Memories of A Catholic Girlhood (1957)
      - Typescript draft: The Prayers of the Poor [Yonder Peasant, Who Is He?] (Folder 11.3)
      - Typescript draft: Yonder Peasant, Who Is He? (Folder 11.4)
      - Typescript draft: A Tin Butterfly (Folder 11.5)
      - Draft for agent, Brandt and Brandt: My Grandfather and Lord Byron [The Blackguard] (Folder 11.6)
      - Typescript draft: The Incognito [C'est le Premier Pas Qui Coûte] (Folder 11.7)
      - Typescript draft: C'est le Premier Pas Qui Coûte (Folder 11.8)
      - Typescript draft: The Two Brothers [The Figures in the Clock] (Folder 11.9)
      - Draft for agent, Brandt and Brandt: The Two Brothers [The Figures in the Clock] (Folder 11.10)
      - Typescript draft: The Figures in the Clock (Folders 11.11 - 11.12)
      - Setting copy [?], p. 106-166 (Folder 12.1)
      - Setting copy: Preface material (Folder 12.2)
      - Setting copy: Pages 1-186 (Folders 12.3 - 12.12)
      - Setting copy: Double Solitaire [Ask Me No Questions] (Folder 12.13)
      - Captions for illustrations, (manuscript) (Folder 13.1)
      - Author's proof for preface material (Folder 13.2)
      - Unrevised galleys (Folder 13.3)
      - Dust jacket and paperback cover (Folder 13.4)
      - American reviews, 1957, undated (Folders 13.5 - 13.7)
      - English reviews (Folder 13.8)
      - Reader mail, 1946-1967, undated (Folders 13.9 - 13.14)
    - The Stones of Florence (1959)
      - Author's notes and clippings (Folder 14.1)
      - Publisher's correspondence, 1959 (Folder 14.2)
      - Correspondence regarding photographs and illustrations, 1958 (Folder 14.3)
      - Research photographs (Folders 14.4 - 14.7)
      - Negatives of photos (Folder 14.8)
      - Original text: Chapters 1-7 (Folders 15.1 - 15.7)
      - Setting copy: Pages 1-83 (Folders 15.8 - 15.11)
      - Setting copy: Pages 84-106, 129, 142-149 (Folder 15.12)
      - Another setting copy: Pages 1-257 [numbering inconsistent or missing pages] (Folders 16.1 - 16.7)
      - Author's page proofs (Folder 16.8)
      - Dust jacket (Folder 16.9)
      - Reader correspondence (Folders 16.10 - 16.11)
      - American reviews (Folder 16.12)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.7)
      - Foreign reviews (Folder 16.13)
    - On the Contrary (1961)
      - Drafts: America the Beautiful (Folder 17.1)
      - Drafts: The Contagion of Ideas (Folder 17.2)
      - Typescript draft: Artists in Uniform [version 1?] (Folder 17.3)
      - Typescript draft: Artists in Uniform [part of final version] (Folder 17.4)
      - Typescript draft: The Road to Damascus (My Confession) [3 versions] (Folders 17.5 - 17.7)
      - Typescript draft: Moments of Choice [earliest version of My Confession] (Folder 17.8)
      - Typescript draft: The Road to Damascus (My Confession)[2 versions] (Folders 17.9 - 17.10)
      - Typescript draft: Letter from Portugal with notes (Folder 18.1)
      - Typescript draft: Up the Ladder from Charm to Vogue (Folder 18.2)
      - Notes, galleys: Up the Ladder from Charm to Vogue (Folder 18.3)
      - Research for "The Vassar Girl" ( Holiday, May 1951) (Folders 18.4 - 18.5)
      - Correspondence with Vassar College regarding "The Vassar Girl" (Folder 18.6)
      - Letter to editor of Holiday on Vassar article (Folder 18.7)
      - Typescript drafts: The American Realist Playwrights (published version of BBC broadcast) (Folder 18.8)
      - Setting copy: A Letter to the Editor of Politics (Folder 19.1)
      - Setting copy: America the Beautiful (Folder 19.2)
      - Setting copy: Gandhi (Folder 19.3)
      - Setting copy: Mlle. Gulliver en Amérique (Folder 19.4)
      - Setting copy: No News, or What Killed the Dog? (Folder 19.5)
      - Setting copy: The Contagion of Ideas (Folder 19.6)
      - Setting copy: Artists in Uniform (Folder 19.7)
      - Setting copy: My Confession (Folder 19.8)
      - Setting copy: Letter from Portugal (Folder 19.9)
      - Setting copy: Mister Rodriguez of Lisbon (Folder 19.10)
      - Setting copy: Naming Names (Folder 19.11)
      - Setting copy: The Vita Activa (Folder 19.12)
      - Setting copy: Tyranny of the Orgasm (Folder 19.13)
      - Setting copy: Up the Ladder from Charm to Vogue (Folder 19.14)
      - Setting copy: The Vassar Girl (Folder 19.15)
      - Setting copy: Recalled to Life ... (Folder 19.16)
      - Setting copy: Settling the Colonel's Hash (Folder 19.17)
      - Setting copy: An Academy of Risk (Folder 19.18)
      - Setting copy: The Fact in Fiction (Folder 19.19)
      - Setting copy: Characters in Fiction (Folder 19.20)
      - Setting copy: The American Realist Playwrights (Folder 19.21)
      - Proofs: Characters in Fiction, Partisan Review, 3-4/1961 (Folder 19.22)
      - Ma Confession, Preuves, December 1963 (Folder 20.1)
      - America the Beautiful, Commentary, September 1947 (Folder 20.2)
      - Mlle. Gulliver en Afrique, reprinted from The Reporter, 22 January 1952 (Folder 20.3)
      - Characters in Fiction Partisan Review, March-April 1961 (Folder 20.4)
      - Realisten im Amerikanischen Drama, Dokumente, December 1961 (Folder 20.5)
      - My Confession, Encounter (Folder 20.6)
      - The Vassar Girl, Queen, 8 May 1962 (Folder 20.7)
      - Reader mail (Folder 20.8)
      - Draft reviews (Folder 20.9)
      - Published reviews (Folder 20.10)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.4)
    - Mary McCarthy's Theatre Chronicles (1963)
      - Typescript draft: Introduction (Folder 21.1)
      - Typescript draft: Sheep in Wolfes' Clothing (Folder 21.2)
      - Typescript draft: A New Word (Folder 21.3)
      - Typescript draft: Odd Man In (Folder 21.4)
      - Reviews (Folder 21.5)
    - The Group (1963)
      - Notes: "Desperate Thoughts About the Novel," Bocca de Magra, 14 August 1960; (mimeographed typescript) (Folder 302.2)
      - Notes: The Group (Folder 21.6)
      - Research material: Vassar publications (Folder 21.7)
      - Typescript draft: On the writing of The Group (Folder 21.8)
      - Correspondence: MM to Hans Hertel, Danish publisher, Arena, 1964 (Folder 21.9)
      - Correspondence: Publishers, 1964 (Folder 21.10)
      - Correspondence: Movie version of The Group, 1963-1964, 1984, undated (Folder 21.11)
      - [Husted story] (Folder 22.1)
      - Typescript draft: Chapters 4-6 (Folders 22.2 - 22.10)
      - "Dottie Makes an Honest Woman of Herself," Partisan Review, January-February 1954 [later chapter 3] (Folder 22.11)
      - "Polly Andrews, Class of '33," New Yorker, 29 June 1963 [later chapter 11-12] (Folder 22.12)
      - Reader correspondence, 1963-1970, undated (Folders 23.1 - 23.4)
      - Correspondence: Master's thesis, 1975 (Folder 23.5)
      - Correspondence: MM to New York Herald Tribune regarding review, 16 February 1964 (Folder 23.6)
      - Correspondence: Partisan Review regarding draft of review (Folder 23.7)
      - English language reviews, 1963-1968, undated (Folder 23.8)
      - Foreign language reviews (Folders 23.9 - 23.11)
      - Scrapbook (Folder 24.1)
      - Galley proofs: French edition (Folder 24.2)
      - The film — Screenplay by Sidney Buchman, (2 versions) (Folders 24.3 - 24.4)
      - The film — Famous Artists Productions records (Folder 24.5)
      - The film — Publicity stills (Folder 24.6)
      - Print of paperback cover (Folder [Box 291])
      - "Aftermath: A Letter from Mary McCarthy," New York Herald Tribune, 8 March 1964 (Folder 393.2 (Oversize))
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 300.5)
    - Vietnam (1967)
      - Notebook (Folder 25.1)
      - Notes, (manuscript) (Folder 25.2)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter I variants: The Home Program (Folders 25.3 - 25.4)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter II variants: The Problems of Success (Folders 25.5 - 25.7)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter III variants: Intellectuals (Folders 25.8 - 25.9)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter IV: Solutions [4 versions] (Folders 25.10 - 25.13)
      - Typescript drafts: fragments (Folder 25.14)
      - Setting copy (Folders 26.1 - 26.4)
      - Cover dummy (Folder 26.5)
      - Page format for dummy copies: Chapter I: The Home Program (Folder 26.6)
      - Page proofs (Folders 26.7 - 26.9)
      - Page proofs (Folders 27.1 - 27.6)
      - Publishers' correspondence, 1967, undated (Folders 28.1 - 28.2)
      - Correspondence regarding Diana Trilling, 1967-1968 (Folder 28.3)
      - Promotional material (Folder 28.4)
      - American reviews (Folder 28.5)
      - Foreign reviews (Folder 28.6)
    - Hanoi (1968)
      - Notes, (manuscript) (Folder 29.1)
      - Notebooks, (2) (Folder 29.2)
      - Typescript draft: Foreword (Folder 29.3)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter I, version A (Folder 29.4)
      - Typescript variants: Chapter I (Folders 29.5 - 29.6)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter II, version A (Folder 29.7)
      - Typescript variants: Chapter II (Folders 29.8 - 29.11)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter III (Folder 29.12)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter III (Folder 29.13)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter IV, version A (Folder 29.14)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter IV (Folder 29.15)
      - Typescript draft: Chapter V, version A (Folder 29.16)
      - Typescript drafts: fragments (Folder 29.17)
      - Galleys (Folders 29.18 - 29.19)
      - Galleys for article: "Hanoi," New York Review of Books, 23 May 1968 (Folder 29.20)
      - Page proofs: Foreword for On Withdrawal... (Folder 30.1)
      - Page proofs: Hanoi - March 1968 (Folder 30.2)
      - Page proofs: The Party Car (Folder 30.3)
      - Page proofs: North Vietnamese Bucolic (Folder 30.4)
      - Page proofs: Language (Folder 30.5)
      - Page proofs: First Principles (Folder 30.6)
      - Publishers' correspondence, 1967-1969, undated (Folders 31.1 - 31.4)
      - Reader correspondence, May-December 1968, undated (Folder 31.5)
    - The Writing on the Wall (1970)
      - Notes: Thoughts about MacBeth [General MacBeth], (manuscript) (Folder 31.6)
      - Notes: A Bolt from the Blue, (manuscript) (Folder 31.7)
      - Notes: J. D. Salinger's Closed Circuit, (manuscript) (Folder 31.8)
      - Notes: Burroughs' Naked Lunch, (manuscript) (Folder 31.9)
      - Notes: The Hue and Cry, with pamphlet, "The Strange World of Hannah Arendt,", 1963; (manuscript) (Folder 31.10)
      - Notes: On Madame Bovary, (manuscript) (Folder 31.11)
      - Notes: The Inventions of Compton-Burnett, (manuscript) (Folder 31.12)
      - Notes: The Writing on the Wall, (manuscript) (Folder 31.13)
      - Notes: Hanging by a Thread, (manuscript) (Folder 31.14)
      - Notes: A Touch of Nature, (manuscript and typescript) (Folder 31.15)
      - Typescript variants: General MacBeth (Folder 31.16)
      - Typescript variants: J. D. Salinger's Closed Circuit (Folders 31.17 - 31.18)
      - Typescript variants: A Bolt from the Blue (Folder 31.19)
      - Typescript variants: Burroughs' Naked Lunch (Folder 32.1)
      - Typescript variants: The Hue and Cry (Folders 32.2 - 32.4)
      - Typescript variants: On Madame Bovary (Folder 32.5)
      - Typescript variants: On Madame Bovary — French translation rejected by McCarthy (Folder 32.6)
      - Typescript variants: Crushing a Butterfly (Folder 32.7)
      - Typescript variants: The Inventions of Compton-Burnett (Folder 32.8)
      - Typescript draft: The Inventions of Compton-Burnett, later variant [3 versions] (Folders 32.9 - 32.11)
      - Typescript draft: More on Compton-Burnett, version A, with a manuscript note (Folder 32.12)
      - Typescript draft: The Writing on the Wall [3 versions] (Folders 32.13 - 32.15)
      - Typescript draft: One Touch of Nature, (fragments) (Folder 32.16)
      - Typescript draft: One Touch of Nature, (photocopy) (Folder 32.17)
      - Setting copy: General MacBeth, introductory pages (Folder 33.1)
      - Setting copy: A Bolt from the Blue (Folder 33.2)
      - Setting copy: J. D. Salinger's Closed Circuit (Folder 33.3)
      - Setting copy: The Hue and Cry (Folder 33.4)
      - Setting copy: On Madame Bovary (Folder 33.5)
      - Setting copy: Crushing a Butterfly (Folder 33.6)
      - Setting copy: The Inventions of Compton-Burnett (Folder 33.7)
      - Setting copy: More on Compton-Burnett (Folder 33.8)
      - Setting copy: The Writing on the Wall (Folder 33.9)
      - Setting copy: Hanging by a Thread (Folder 33.10)
      - Setting copy: One Touch of Nature (Folder 33.11)
      - Setting copy: [all chapters] (Folder 33.12)
      - Galley proofs: marked set (Folder 34.1)
      - Dust jacket dummy (Folder 35.1)
      - Dust jackets (U.S. and English editions) (Folder 35.2)
      - Proofs (with corrections) of book (Folder 35.3)
      - Proofs of article: The Inventions of Compton-Burnett, Encounter, November 1966 (Folder 35.4)
      - Proofs of article: Burroughs' Naked Lunch, Encounter, April 1963 (Folder 35.5)
      - Proofs of article: One Touch of Nature, The New Yorker, 24 January 1970, with publisher's correspondence, 1969 (Folder 35.6)
      - Proofs of article: "Eine Prise Natur" (German) (Folder 35.7)
      - Article: General MacBeth, Harper's Magazine, June 1962 (Folder 35.8)
      - Article: A Bolt from the Blue, New Republic, 4 June 1962, with McCarthy letter to the Editor, 25 June 1962 (Folder 35.9)
      - Article: A Bolt from the Blue, Encounter, October 1962 (Folder 35.10)
      - Article: The Writing on the Wall, The New York Review of Books, no date (Folder 35.11)
      - Article: Hanging by a Thread, The New York Review of Books, 31 July 1969 (Folder 35.12)
      - Correspondence: The Writing on the Wall, 1969-1970 (Folder 35.13)
      - Correspondence: General MacBeth, 1962-1966, undated (Folder 35.14)
      - Correspondence: A Bolt from the Blue, June 1962, undated (Folder 35.15)
      - Correspondence: J. D. Salinger's Closed Circuit, 1962-1963, undated (Folder 35.16)
      - Correspondence: Burroughs' Naked Lunch, 1963-1965, undated (Folder 35.17)
      - Correspondence: The Hue and Cry, 1963-1964, undated (Folder 35.18)
      - Correspondence: "On Madame Bovary, 1964-1968 (Folder 35.19)
      - Correspondence: One Touch of Nature, January-June 1970 (Folder 35.20)
      - Clippings and reviews: J. D. Salinger's Naked Lunch " (Folder 36.1)
      - Clippings and reviews: The Naked Lunch (Folder 36.2)
      - Draft reviews: The Hue and Cry (Folder 36.3)
      - Clippings and reviews: The Hue and Cry (Folder 36.4)
      - Clippings and reviews: The Inventions of Compton-Burnett (Folder 36.5)
      - Clippings and reviews: One Touch of Nature (Folder 36.6)
      - Reviews: The Writing on the Wall (Folders 36.7 - 36.10)
      - Related reviews: The Writing on the Wall (Folder 36.11)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.9)
    - Winter Visitors (1970 - Limited edition)
      - Galley proofs: marked set (Folder 43.1)
      - Corrected galleys (Folder 43.2)
      - Author's page proofs (Folder 43.3)
      - Publisher's correspondence, 1970-1971, undated (Folders 44.1 - 44.2)
    - Birds of America (1971)
      - Research notes (Folders 37.1 - 37.2)
      - Research publications (Folder 37.3)
      - Notes (Folders 37.4 - 37.5)
      - Typescript draft: "On the Writing of Birds of America " [for the Franklin Library edition] (Folder 37.6)
      - Typescript variants: Chapter 1. Winter Visitors (Folders 37.7 - 37.15)
      - Typescript variants: Chapter 2. The Battle of Rocky Port (Folders 38.1 - 38.5)
      - Typescript variants: Chapter 3. To Be a Pilgrim (Folders 38.6 - 38.10)
      - Typescript variants: Chapter 4. Epistle From Mother Carey's Chicken, (7 versions) (Folders 38.11 - 38.17)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter 5, version A. Greek Fire (Folders 39.1 - 39.5)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter 6 [orig. 7]. Round Table, With the Damsel Parcenet, (photocopy) (Folder 39.6)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter 6, (photocopy) (Folder 39.7)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter 7 [orig. 6]. Leviticus (Folders 40.1 - 40.6)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter 9 [no. 8]. A Sybilline Interlude (Folders 40.7 - 40.11)
      - Typescript variant: Chapter 10. Two-thirds of a Ghost (Folders 41.1 - 41.3)
      - Typescript variant: Chapters 2-6 (Folder 316.3)
      - Setting copy: Chapters 1-10 (Folders 41.4 - 41.13)
      - Corrected page proofs: all chapters (Folders 42.1 - 42.10)
      - Galley corrections: Chapter 9 (Folder 42.11)
      - Foreign Publishers' correspondence, 1971-1972, undated (Folder 44.3)
      - Publishers' correspondence, 1969-1972, undated (Folders 44.4 - 44.6)
      - Publicity (Folder 44.7)
      - Reader correspondence, 1969-1979, undated (Folders 44.8 - 44.9)
      - Interviews (Folder 45.1)
      - Reviews (Folders 45.2 - 45.10)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 300.1)
    - Medina (1972)
      - Background of trial participants (Folder 46.1)
      - News releases from Fort McPherson, March-April 1970 (Folder 46.2)
      - Court transcript of U.S. vs. Medina, September 1971 (Folder 46.3)
      - Notes (Folder 46.4)
      - Notes and memorabilia from Medina trial with a note from A. Young, 7 September 1971 (Folder 46.5)
      - Clippings (Folders 46.6 - 46.9)
      - Typescript variants, (8 versions) (Folders 47.1 - 47.8)
      - Correspondence: writing and publication of Medina, 1971-1973, undated (Folders 47.9 - 47.10)
      - Article: "Reflections: A Transition Figure," The New Yorker, 10 June 1972 (Folder 47.11)
      - Setting copy (Folder 48.1)
      - Corrected page proofs (Folder 48.2)
      - Page proofs, p. 1-87 (Folders 48.3 - 48.5)
      - Cover design (Folder 48.6)
      - Reviews, 1972-1973, undated (Folder 48.7)
    - Can There Be a Gothic Literature? (1973)
      - Research material (Folders 48A.1 - 48A.3)
      - Notes, (manuscript) (Folder 48A.4)
      - Typescript variants (Folder 48A.5)
      - Typescript drafts (Folders 48A.6 - 48A.7)
      - [Setting copy?] (Folder 48A.8)
      - [Corrected galley fragment?] (Folder 48A.9)
      - Corrected proof (Folder 48A.10)
    - The Seventeenth Degree (1974)
      - Typescript variants: Preface [How It Went] (Folder 49.1)
      - Letter, 19 Nov 1973 (Folder 49.2)
      - Typescript draft: Preface [How It Went], (photocopy) (Folder 49.2)
      - Notebook: Halberstam [Sons of the Morning] (Folder 49.3)
      - Typescript variants: Halberstam [Sons of the Morning] (Folder 49.4)
      - Typescript draft: Halberstam [Sons of the Morning] (Folder 49.5)
      - Galley copy: How It Went (Folder 49.6)
      - Setting copy: The Seventeenth Degree (Folders 49.7 - 49.9)
      - [Galley?]: Article: "Sons of the Morning," The New York Review of Books, 25 January 1973 (Folder 49.10)
      - Galley proofs: The Seventeenth Degree (Folders 49.11 - 49.12)
      - Page proofs: The Seventeenth Degree (Folders 50.1 - 50.5)
      - Corrected page proofs: The Seventeenth Degree (Folders 50.6 - 50.8)
      - Correspondence re: "Sons of the Morning" [article] (Folder 50.9)
      - Correspondence: The Seventeenth Degree and review (including letter from Al Capp) (Folder 50.10)
      - Interview transcript: "Kaleidoscope" on BBC, 21 February 1975 (Folder 50.11)
      - Reviews: "Sons of the Morning" [article] (Folder 50.12)
      - Reviews: The Seventeenth Degree (Folder 50.13)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 301.5)
    - Mask of State (1974 June)
      - Typescript draft: Watergate Notes (Folders 51.1 - 51.12)
      - Typescript draft: Watergate Notes, (fragment) (Folder 51.13)
      - Typescript draft: "Postscript to Nixon", (photocopy) (Folder 51.14)
      - Setting copy (Folders 52.1 - 52.9)
      - Galley proofs: author's marked set (Folder 52.10)
      - Corrected page proofs (Folders 53.1 - 53.5)
      - Watergate trip — correspondence and notes (Folder 53.6)